MOHAMMED ZULFIQAR

SENIOR ARCHITECTURAL CAD TECHNICIAN



PERSONAL INFORMATION



+918445662707



https://bit.ly/45yvWE1



zulfigarmohd0108atgmaildotcom



LinkedIn



Aligarh, INDIA

CORE SKILLS

- · Architectural CAD Design & Drafting
- AutoCAD Proficiency
- Architectural Detailing & Technical Drawings
- Team Leadership & Supervision
- Project Coordination & Communication
- Municipality Compliance & Submission Drawings
- Time Management & Efficiency

EDUCATION

- Diploma in Drafting & Designing-Aligarh Muslim University, India (1986 – 1989)
- Certification Course in AutoCAD-Aligarh, India (1992)
- Certification Course in Revit- Dubai, UAE (2019)

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a Senior Architectural CAD Technician with over 35 years of hands-on experience in architectural drafting and detailing, including 25 years in the UAE.

I have contributed to a wide range of projects across the Middle East. My work spans high-rise residential and commercial towers, hospitals, government buildings, and large-scale mixed-use developments.

I specialize in producing accurate, coordinated architectural drawings that meet project requirements and design standards. I pay close attention to detail and focus on preparing clear and accurate design drawings that support the overall project process.

WORK EXPERIENCE

- Al Fakhama Architects—Erbil, Iraq (March 2023 to March 2024)
- Bob Atwal Associates—Mumbai, India (June 2022 to Sep 2022)
- Parsons International—Dubai, UAE (Sep 2015 to Nov 2019)
- BEAD Architects & Engineers—Abu Dhabi, UAE (Jan 2013 to Aug 2015)
- Sahil Engineering Consultant—Abu Dhabi, UAE (March 2011 to Sep 2012)
- Arkonsult Engineering Consultant—Abu Dhabi, UAE (Nov 2009 to Jan 2011)
- Cap Concept Architectural & Planning—Abu Dhabi, UAE (Dec 2007 to Jan 2009)
- Arif & Bintoak Consulting Architects & Engineers—Dubai, UAE (Nov 2003 to Oct 2007)
- MA Malik Architects—India (June 2000 to Oct 2003)
- Six Construct Limited—Dubai, UAE (June 1992 to May 2000)
- The Design Group—New Delhi, India (Aug 1989 to May 1992)

KEY PROJECTSLandmark Projects

- Dubai Expo 2020-District and Parks, Food Halls, Water Features, South Park, Observation Tower, Street Market Restaurant, North Park—Multi-Concept and Family Offer and Kiosks.
- Intelligent Traffic System for Dubai (ITS-2020).
 Ground + Mezzanine + First Floor + Roof.
- Basra Appeal Court, Basra, Iraq.
 Ground + First + Roof Floor.
- Concorde Tower at Jumeirah Lake Tower, Dubai.
 3B + G + 43 + 2 mechanical floors.
 Total built-up area = 570,901 sq. ft.
- Shary Jwan Millennium 5 Star Hotel, Iraq.
 G + M + SF + 30 Floors.
- Saraya Residential Towers, Abu Dhabi.
 3B + G + M + Amenity + Service Floor + 32 Floors.
- Total built-up area = 454,545 sq. ft.

JOB RESPONSIBILITIES

- Supervision of team of Architectural Technologists to prepare Working Drawings and Submission Drawings.
- Preparation of detailed Architectural Working Drawings, including Plans, Elevations, Sections, Wall Sections and Schedules of Openings.
- Developing specialized details such as substations, garbage enclosures, ramps, staircases, kitchens, bathrooms, and swimming pool as per Project Manager and Architects' briefs.
- Preparation of submission drawings in compliance with municipality regulations.
- Integrating structural and MEP
 designs into architectural plans,
 sections, and wall sections to ensure
 cohesive and functional designs.
 This process involves close
 collaboration with engineers to
 address any potential conflicts and
 optimize the overall design.
 Additionally, it is essential to
 maintain clear communication with
 all stakeholders throughout the
 project to facilitate timely revisions
 and approvals.

LANGUAGES

- English
- Urdu

Residential & Commercial Projects

- Jangid Elysium Tower-Imprint Construction—Mumbai, India.
 Ground + 4 Podiums + 30 Floors.
- Faruk Holding Asiacell Headquarters, Iraq. 3B + G + 20 Floors.
- Julfar Residential Tower, Al Reem Island, Abu Dhabi.
 2B + G + 23 Floors.
- Residential Building in Media City, Dubai. 2B + G + 14 Floors.
 Total built-up area = 260,315 sq. ft.
- Residential Building for H/E Sheikh Manna bin Khalifa Al Maktoum at Jadaf Dubai. B + G + 7 Floors.
 Total built-up area = 150,413 sq. ft.
- Residential Building for Mr. Rashed Majid Al Muhaire at al Murqabat Dubai. B + G + 7 Floors.
 Total built-up area = 148,486 sq. ft.
- Residential & Commercial Building for Al Gurair at al Murqabat Dubai. 2B + G + M + 7 Floors.
 Total built-up area = 235,672 sq. ft.
- Commercial & Office Building for Mohammad Saeed Khalaf Al Ghaith at Port Saeed Dubai. 3B + G + 13 + Gymnasium Floors. Total built-up area = 200,269 sq. ft.
- Commercial & Office Building DSC Gateway Towers at Dubai Sports City, Dubai. 3B + G + 44 Floors.
- Residential Building Al Furjan Tower at Jabel Ali First 591, Dubai.
 2B + G + 13 Floors.
- Residential Building Al Khail Gate, Al Qouz, Dubai. G + 5 Floors.
- Mosque Plots SP4-C01, Saadiyat Island for Saadiyat Development and Investment Company, Abu Dhabi.
 Ground + First + Roof Floor.

Healthcare & Infrastructure Projects

- Baghdad Hospital: Centre of Life Project, Harithiya for Dar Alsabah Co Ltd- Iraq. 2B + G + 3 Floors.
- 100 Beds Hospital at Safwan, Basra, Iraq. G + 3 Floors.
- Al Taweelah Power & Desalination Plant Stage' B, Water & Electricity Department, Abu Dhabi.